NICHOLAS MICHUDA - SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Chicago, IL | 630-360-1160 | nmichuda@gmail.com | GitHub

SUMMARY

Highly motivated and hardworking full-stack software engineer committed to building a successful career in software development. Proficiency with both front-end and back-end programming gained through comprehensive software engineering bootcamp. 3 years experience working in a professional engineering environment demonstrating attention to detail and problem solving abilities.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Software: Javascript, Python, C++, React, HTML, CSS, Node.js

Tools: Mocha, Chai, Git, GitHub, Node Package Manager, and Visual Studio Code

Additional Skills: Mandarin (conversational)

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING PROJECTS

Flashcard Study App | Thinkful | Project Link

09/2023

- Assembled the functionality for an application that allows the user to create, edit, and study flashcards.
- Coded using React components to enable easy expansion of the application with no need for code refactoring.
- Technology: Javascript ES6, Node.js, React, Bootstrap

Movie Database Application | Project Link

11/2023

- Assembled the back end of a movie website allowing any user to search for their favorite movies.
- Used CRUD methods for reviews, and view theaters and movies that are showing.
- Applied router and controller functions to retrieve a user's specific requests.
- Technology: Node.js, Express, and Knex. Version control with Git.

Restaurant Reservation Application | Project Link

12/2023

- Worked with a full stack reservation and table management system.
- Implemented a React router and Express to build a RESTful API, to make HTTP requests for all the reservation data stored in the connected PostgreSQL database.
- Created CRUD functions and Knex queries to handle data going to and coming from the database.
- Technology: Node.js, Express, Knex, PostgreSQL

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Emcore Corporation Tinley Park, IL 08/2022 - 07/2023

R&D Engineer

- Led efforts to debug and repair failing electrical hardware, effectively reducing manufacturing fallout.
- Worked with mechanical engineering team to develop new circuit boards and cables.
- Collaborated with a cross-functional team to develop test fixtures for next generation fiber optic gyroscopes.

KVH Industries

Electrical Engineer

Tinley Park, IL

06/2020 - 08/2022

- Designed schematics and layouts for multi-layer circuit boards using Altium Designer.
- Provided complete circuit board manufacturing data to board fabrication houses.
- Led design and fabrication efforts for printed circuit boards used for testing and debugging new designs.

EDUCATION

Thinkful

Certificate, Software Engineering Program

Online

06/2023 - 01/2024

- Learned industry best practices and software development standards with a focus on JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, React Native, and Node.js.
- Developed and deployed mobile-first applications while learning new languages and frameworks, learning from senior web developers in a mentor-student relationship.

Vanderbilt University Nashville, TN